Allan Kyebambe

allankyebambe@gmail.com / akyebambe@drt-ug.org

+256 - 758686127 / 786117582

Zone B Makerere II, Nanfumbambi Road, Kampala Uganda

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have 2 years' experience in IT systems and Solutions with a deeper understanding of both hardware and software systems such as content management systems, internet and network troubleshooting and maintenance, GIS, ICT support services and IT related research and analysis. Am a self-motivated ICT professional, dedicated, flexible, with a positive attitude towards work and high sense of integrity. Leadership is also part of my spheres of influence.

EDUCATION

2013-2017- Bsc. Computer Science (2nd Class Upper Hons) Makerere

University

2017 Google Online Marketing Certificate

2013-2014 Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Module, Grade A

Makerere University

2011-2012 Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education

Old Kampala Senior Secondary School

2006-2009 Uganda Certificate of Education

Kawaala College School

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2018 to date: GIS Expert, Empowering Local and Humanitarian Actors Project: In charge of designing data collection application for incorporating GIS modules in the system and developing Hazards, Risks and Vulnerability maps.

June 2017 to date: Information and Communication Technology Officer – Development Research and Training: In charge of implementing the IT applications and systems, ICT end user support, managing the Office Network (WANs and LANs) and ICT Resources, Backup and executing the ICT disaster Recovery Plan, administering the company website and performing all other ICT related duties.

October 2016 to date: IT Support Officer, Community Based Monitoring System – Development Research and Training: In charge of offering all the IT support services, cleaning and consolidation of the CBMS database, Developing Poverty maps, Installation and updating of the CBMS Scan on the IT gadgets and data validation.

June 2016 – May 2017: Graduate Trainee(Volunteer) ICT Unit- Development Research and Training: Responsible for monitoring the functioning of servers of the ICT Unit at DRT, making routine system check-ups of the computer and internet

systems, scheduling and making back-ups of all computer systems and On user IT support to staff and capacity building in ICT related areas.

June 2015 – August 2015: IT Internee, College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences (ICT Unit)-Makerere University: Responsible for monitoring the functioning of servers in the ICT Unit at CAES, developing websites for School of Food Technology, Nutrition and Bio-Engineering Makerere University, troubleshooting computer systems using airdrop especially Systems Extensions and Libraries, training staff about Microsoft packages, ICT systems and installation of Windows OS and other IT support services at school of Forestry GIS Unit.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE:

April 2015 – May 2016: President School of Computing and Informatics Technology Makerere University: I was in charge of coordinating all students in the school of computing and Informatics Technology, representing the students' fraternity at all levels of administration (College Administration Boards), organizing student engaging activities like sports gala and cleanliness awareness and preparing Reports on Status of study processes (performance efficiency).

March 2015 – March 2016: Fellowship Coordinator School of Computing and Informatics Technology Makerere University: I was responsible for coordinating all fellowship activities and scheduling them.

SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

- 1. ICT/ Computer Systems: Well conversant with GIS skills and Microsoft office applications Like MS Word, MS Excel, MS Access, MS PowerPoint and Presentation,
 - Working with content management systems, installation of Windows Operating systems and other related software, installation of Various Computer Peripheral devices such as wireless cards, Printers, scanners, termination of various types of Network Cables such as Straight through, Cross Over cables, troubleshooting Network problems using Basic TCP/IP Connectivity test, network management and troubleshooting Computer Systems Libraries and extensions.
- 2. Administration/ Leadership: I exhibit Interpersonal skills, planning, budgeting, report Writing and Leadership with a high tolerance level
- 3. Languages(Fluency): English, Runkyakitara and Luganda



1. Dr Agnes Rwashana

Deputy Principal College of Computing and Information Sciences, Makerere University

Email: asemwanga@cit.ac.ug

Tel: +256 772412438

2. Prof. Engineer Bainomugisha

Head of Department Computer Science, Makerere University

Tel: +256 794665051

Email: baino@cis.mak.ac.ug

3. Mr James Kisoro

CEO – Billbrain Technologies Tel:

+256 702841395.

Email: jamesk.k10@gmail.com